<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Bheemsen Kulkarni</title>
    <link>https://bhimsen92.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Bheemsen Kulkarni</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2023 01:20:00 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://bhimsen92.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A Template for System Design</title>
      <link>https://bhimsen92.github.io/posts/2023/06/a-template-for-system-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2023 01:20:00 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bhimsen92.github.io/posts/2023/06/a-template-for-system-design/</guid>
      <description>Designing a software system is difficult, especially when you don&amp;rsquo;t have a plan or a set of instructions. But once you have a plan to guide you, it becomes easier to solve the problem step by step. In this blog, I will share a few things I learned from reading online and my own experience about how to approach system design questions at work or in interviews.&#xA;Problem statement To begin, it is important to accurately define the problem statement.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Learnings From Work and Life</title>
      <link>https://bhimsen92.github.io/posts/2023/05/learnings-from-work-and-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 May 2023 10:54:00 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bhimsen92.github.io/posts/2023/05/learnings-from-work-and-life/</guid>
      <description>As a sofware engineer with ten years of experience, I have seen many ups and downs. This has taught me many things both professionally and personally. Here is a summary of those learnings.&#xA;If you possess knowledge, it is impossible for anyone to deceive or trick you. Follow Boys Scout Rule as much as possible. Learn about XY problem and avoid following into its traps. 5 Whys technique can be effective in preventing the XY problem.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How To Learn New Programming Language Quickly</title>
      <link>https://bhimsen92.github.io/posts/2023/01/how-to-learn-new-programming-language-quickly/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jan 2023 22:50:00 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bhimsen92.github.io/posts/2023/01/how-to-learn-new-programming-language-quickly/</guid>
      <description>Our job requires us to learn new programming languages once in a while. Some languages are easy while others have steep learning curve. I would have wished if there was a templte for learning languages because each language has similar concepts but with different syntax. Once you understand what is common between the language you know and the language you want to learn, all that is left is to master the syntax which comes with some practice.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rabbitmq Tutorial</title>
      <link>https://bhimsen92.github.io/posts/2021/01/rabbitmq-tutorial/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2021 05:27:22 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bhimsen92.github.io/posts/2021/01/rabbitmq-tutorial/</guid>
      <description>Before I write about Rabbitmq, let&amp;rsquo;s briefly talk about what message queues are in the first place. Message Queue is a programming paradigm which is used for inter process communication where proceses are running either on the same machine or on different machines.&#xA;When your design requires loose coupling between components, a part of your solution has a cpu intensive operation which can be delgated to a background process, you have to notify multiple components of a certain event then message queue is the solution that you would like to consider for your project.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Python Metaclass and It&#39;s Magic Methods</title>
      <link>https://bhimsen92.github.io/posts/2021/01/python-metaclass-and-its-magic-methods/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2021 23:37:10 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bhimsen92.github.io/posts/2021/01/python-metaclass-and-its-magic-methods/</guid>
      <description>Python is one of my favourite language. It is very intuitive, simple and a powerful language. It&amp;rsquo;s power comes from its ability to give the developers the freedom to manipulate the language at run time. One such ability is how a programmer can intercept the control during class object creation and change its outlook entirely from what programmer intented. This is achieved through a language feature called metaclass.&#xA;metaclass is a class of a class.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://bhimsen92.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bhimsen92.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>A passionate computer programmer, avid movie watcher and a cat lover :)&#xA;Find me on GitHub</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
